# RICHMAN LARRY CLIFFORD | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Kumasi, Ghana | larriche99@gmail.com | +233558127809 | GitHub: http://github.com/larriche

#### **SUMMARY**

A software engineer with about 7 years of active commercial experience building software applications for multiple platforms across the education, automobile, food, pharmaceuticals and foster care and team coaching industries, experienced with remote work and development team management.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: PHP, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, HTML, CSS

Frameworks and Libraries: Laravel, Livewire, Vue.js, React, TailwindCSS, Node.js, MobX, Redux

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Testing: PHPUnit, Chai, Jest, React Testing Library, Dusk

Others: Git, Docker, Web Scraping, CI/CD, REST APIs, Ecommerce, Agile Development, Posthog,

CustomerIO, AWS

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Software Engineer – Valence** 

Toronto, Ontario, Canada(Remote) March 2021 - November 2023

I worked on improving and adding features to a team coaching software and achieved the following:

- Worked on enhancements to surveys and reports for personality tests, team and individual performance and habit tracker tools.
- Updated queries to solve N+1 query problems among other performance improvements.
- Worked on a real-time team games feature that used Server-sent events.
- Worked on re-designing the web app interface and page layout and information architecture.
- Updated Dusk tests to reduce flakiness and wrote new tests for critical app flows.
- Worked on app integrations with CustomerIO, Posthog and Metabase.
- Built tools for Customer Success team using Laravel Nova.
- Enhanced my UX skills working hand in hand with product designers to design new features and using my discretion to implement solutions in the absence of provided UI designs.

**SKILLS USED:** PHP, Laravel, JavaScript, Typescript, React, REST APIs, MySQL, Node.js, MobX, Git, Kanban

Software Engineer – GRG Ezitek Solutions Kumasi, Ghana October 2017 – March 2021

I worked as a software engineer at this Ghanaian-based software agency that I co-founded and achieved the following:

- Developed an online food delivery service where I was the main developer for the REST API powering the service as well as the main website and the admin panels. I also did a bit of system administration work.
- Wrote scripts in PHP and Python for utility purposes such as data scraping, image processing, data backups among others.

- Developed a results collation system that was deployed for a political party in one of the electoral constituencies during the 2020 general elections in Ghana. It was used for real-time results monitoring and ingested data from a mobile app and USSD service.
- Served as a team lead for a group of 4 engineers. I conducted daily standups and allocated tasks on our various projects.

**SKILLS USED:** PHP, Laravel, JavaScript, Jquery, Vue.js, React, REST APIs, MySQL, AWS, Jenkins, Web scraping, Git, Ecommerce, Tailwind, Livewire, Agile Development, JIRA, Node.js, Express, Web Sockets, PHPUnit, Jest, Chai, Vagrant, USSD, Docker

# Software Engineer – Clearcare Solutions Stafford, UK(Remote) October 2018 – October 2020

As part of a contract that had Ezitek Solutions' engineers consulting for Clearcare Solutions - a leading provider of foster care homes management software across the UK, I achieved the following:

- Worked in a team to migrate their legacy PHP codebase to a modern PHP5 through 7 codebase using the Laravel framework. This refactoring and migration made it possible for more features to be easily added to the software.
- Worked on advanced enhancements to a form builder and task logs editor component of the software.
- Built a custom dashboard design tool that had customizable widgets.
- Worked on query optimizations to reduce load times of some critical components of the application drastically.
- Worked in a team to develop the main Clearcare software's UI in Vue.js which made it sleeker and more responsive and allowed for richer user experiences to be developed.
- Answered technical support tickets on Zendesk.
- Implemented logic for state management aspects of a mobile app.
- Worked with the technical lead and project manager to plan the migration of the system to AWS from its hosting provider at the time.

**SKILLS USED:** PHP, Laravel, JavaScript, Jquery, Vue.js, MySQL, PHPUnit, Jest, Chai, Vagrant, Git, Jenkins, AWS

# Web Developer – Scopic Software Massachusetts, USA(Remote) May 2017 – December 2018

I worked remotely as a web development consultant for client projects at Scopic Software, a virtual software company based in the United States. My team included engineers of various experience levels and from US, Russia, Ukraine, Serbia, the UK among others.

- I worked on the CRM software for a US-based car dealership chain where I built an analytics dashboard, built the UI for a wizard for creating SMS-based and social media campaigns using the Facebook SDK and partnered with engineers at an AI startup to integrate their chatbot API for automated customer service as requested by client. I also worked on refactoring and adding of new features to the application core.
- Worked on an admin panel for a pharmaceutical company. This involved development of scripts to import medical data from excel files and displaying them using a rich admin panel interface from where new data could be entered or modifications made.
- Received training on Wordpress, Django, Node.js and React
- Built a Wordpress plugin into a client's real estate property listings website for pulling information from various data sources.
- Attained experience of remote work, working on multiple projects at a time and agile development.

**SKILLS USED:** HTML, CSS, PHP, Laravel, JavaScript, Jquery, Wordpress, BlinkAI API, Facebook SDK, Node.js, Git, JIRA, Linux

#### Freelance Software Developer

Kumasi, Ghana February 2015 – May 2017

I worked as a freelancer building software mostly for student projects using desktop and web technologies.

- Built a REST API for the mobile app of a restaurant and deployed on AWS
- Worked on a small social network forum for connecting students but project was stopped by client.
- Built a quiz software for first year students at my university to practice for Economics MCQ exams using C#. The software won an award at a college apps contest.
- Built a software for a student association in a Ghanaian university for sending SMS and emails as well as maintaining student profiles.
- Built a software for managing the registration of students in a client's chain of schools for various national exams.
- Built a desktop software for reading classic novels which rendered text (obtained from free classic
  novel websites through web scraping) in a graphically exciting way and also had a text to speech
  feature for reading the books out loud to the reader.

**SKILLS USED:** HTML, CSS, PHP, Laravel, JavaScript, Jquery, MySQL, C#, Python, PyQt, Linux, Genetic Algorithms, Git, AWS

### **EDUCATION**

#### **BSc Computer Science**

#### Kwame Nkrumah University Of Science and Technology, Ghana 2015-2019

- Graduated with a first-class honours degree while combining schoolwork with working as a fulltime software developer and being a startup co-founder at some point.
- Won a hackathon organized for universities in Ghana as part of a team of 3 in 2017.
- Served as Research Officer for the Computer Science Society of the school in 2018.
- Inspired and mentored fellow students and juniors to start careers in software development.
- Developed an automated college timetable generation system using genetic algorithms for my final project.

# **LANGUAGES**

English – First language

## TIMEZONE/AVAILABILITY

I am currently based in Ghana (UTC) but I am capable of and have had experience working in other time zones as well as preferred by the company.